ASHTON HOLGATE

Front-End Web Developer

ashtonholgate.dev - ashton.holgate@gmail.com - 07714 619 467



Enthusiastic and ambitious front end web developer with a passion for the web and a love of programming. Creative UI Designer who loves creating beautiful and functional user experiences. Core competencies include **React**, **Redux**, **Typescript**, and **SCSS**. Skilled user of **Adobe Photoshop** and **XD**. Experience using Reselect to memoise data and Redux Sagas to ease asynchronous data requests. Highly skilled at using animations in webapps to enhance aesthetics and increase app intuitiveness by communicating to the user the flow of data within the app.

- PROFICIENCIES -

React

- Typescript
- Redux

Redux Saga

Reselect

HTML

CSS

Animations

- Adobe XD
- Photoshop

- EXPERIENCE -

Luxtripper - Front End Developer & Lead Designer - October 2017 - Present

- · Redesigned and implemented key pages including hotel search, hotel landing, and bespoke itinerary pages
- Designed and created internal sales and lead management system in React, Redux, and Typescript.
- Produced 'Luxtripper Style Guide' to help coordinate design efforts between developers and business

Gemini Design - Head of IT - October 2014 - October 2017

- Implemented and maintained all digital systems including email, cloud storage, shared calendar, task-management software, password management, quotation system, general folder structure protocol, and template-based website.
- Designed, created, and maintained complete Sketchup 'Dynamic Component' library which included a suite of objects that could be resized, and automatically redrawn, by SketchUp. Units utilized sketchup Animate feature wherever possible.

Personal Projects

• Designed and created <u>WhenWillYou.Win</u>, a lottery simulator made in **React**, **Redux**, and **Typescript**. Project exemplifies use of animation to communicate data flow throughout system.

- EDUCATION -

Essex University - BA(Hons) 2:1 Philosophy and Politics - 2010 - 2013

Transferable Skills

- Creating detailed critical analysis so as to generate effective solutions.
- Communicating intricate ideas in concise and easily understood ways.
- Producing articulate and professional documents within tight deadlines.

Education Summary

Philosophical education focused on communicating clearly, and persuasively, to present ideas convincingly through well-structured, systematic, arguments. Trained to have an eye for detail when problem solving and analysing new problems. Studied classical Greek philosophy, 17th century enlightenment ideology, and modern discourse on ethics, politics, and human rights. Organised presentation groups bi-weekly to identify, clarify, and expound upon key topics taught in previous weeks.